

## **Hussein Ayoub**

O Home: faiyum, desya, Desya, 63511, Fayoum, Egypt

**Email:** <u>ha1276@fayoum.edu.eg</u> **Email:** <u>enghussein199260@gmail.com</u>

**Phone:** (+20) 1550479921 **Phone:** (+20) 1063091623

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/hussein-ayoub-4970867b/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/hussein-ayoub-4970867b/</a>

Date of birth: 10/09/1992 Nationality: Egyptian

### **ABOUT ME**

I am looking forward to having this opportunity as a senior technical office engineer, I have 8 years of experience in the construction industry as much as I got knowledge about construction management and primavera. Also, my contact with site issues taught me how to be negotiable, accountable, responsible, and builder of the network. Besides that, I have to mention here that I have studied a pre-master course in construction management mixed with the BIM approach. Since I have this BIM knowledge, I have good experience with Synchro Pro software which is a perfect tool for 4D planning. So, I am so eager to start a new challenge with yours.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

[ 10/01/2022 - Current ]

## **Senior Civil Technical Office Engineer**

### Memaar Al Morshedy

City: Zahra North Coast, Alamein, Sidi Abdel-Rahman

**Country:** Egypt

I have been working on the Zahra project located on the north coast. There are many life facilities including condos, chalets, apartments, and villas. Also, there are many service zones surrounded by swimming pools and artificial lakes. Whereas I handled those responsibilities.

- Managing and overseeing the sequence of the construction cycle.
- Performing accurate quantity surveying for all construction objects.
- Overseeing all project stages from preliminary layouts to final engineering designs.
- Preparing shop drawings for all reinforced components.
- Cost estimation and project schedule.
- Ensuring that construction site objects are completed on time and within budget.
- Documenting processes and presenting project progress updates to senior managers and clients.
- Preparing cash flow and invoices for subcontractors.

[30/06/2018 - 31/12/2021]

## **Senior Civil Technical Office Engineer**

### Memaar Al Morshdey

City: Al-Hayah University, 5th Settlement

**Country:** Egypt

I have worked in Al-Hayah University Educational buildings which have 40 feddans area consisting of 14 buildings of faculties, hospitals, and sports clubs. Since I have got my position as a Senior I handled many responsibilities:

- Maintaining cost control on-site activities.
- Monitoring cost control on-site activities.
- Doing quantity survey activities.
- Preparing, reviewing, and adjusting shop drawings.
- · Managing document control activities on site,
- Preparing client and subcontractors demands/VOs.

[31/12/2017 - 15/06/2018]

### **Senior Civil Site Engineer**

### Memaar Al Morshedy

City: Degla Palms, 6th of October

Country: Egypt

I have worked in Degla Palms residential compound which has 500 feddans area consisting of housing buildings, shopping malls, hospitals, and schools. Since I have got my position as a Senior I handled many responsibilities:

- Managing daily activities according to the standard specifications and standards.
- Ensuring that the project is executed according to the plan and schedule.
- Check that work is going compatible with safety and regulatory standards.
- Negotiating with suppliers, vendors, and subcontractors to secure the best deals.
- Supervising junior engineers and workers crew.
- Reporting to construction managers and senior managers.
- Delegating tasks as required for the team.

[30/06/2015 - 20/12/2017]

## **Junior Civil Site Engineer**

## Memaar Al Morshdey

City: Degla Palms, 6th of October

Country: Egypt

I have worked in Degla Palms residential compound which has 500 feddans area consisting of housing buildings, shopping malls, hospitals, and schools. Since I got my position as a Junior I handled these responsibilities:

- Assisting senior site engineer in managing daily activities.
- Ensuring that the project is implemented according to the plan and schedule.
- Overseeing construction works happening at the site.
- Delivering and requesting the finished works to consultants.
- Implementing construction tasks according to the method of statement.
- Reviewing drawings for the construction proposed works.
- Reporting to senior engineers and construction managers the progress updates for works.

# [ 05/08/2014 - 25/06/2015 ] **Junior Civil Site Engineer**

### Abou Al-Makaram for Contracting.

City: Ishraqa, 6th of October

Country: Egypt

I have worked in Ishraga compound residential compound which has 40 feddans area consisting of housing buildings, shopping malls, hospitals, and schools. Since I got my position as a Junior I handled these responsibilities:

- Assisting senior site engineer in managing daily activities.
- Ensuring that the project is implemented according to the plan and schedule.
- Overseeing construction works happening at the site.
- Delivering and requesting the finished works to consultants.
- Implementing construction tasks according to the method of statement.
- Reviewing drawings for the construction proposed works.
- Reporting to senior engineers and construction managers the progress updates for works.

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

[ 01/09/2009 - 17/05/2014 ]

## **B.Sc in Civil Engineering**

Fayoum University <a href="http://www.fayoum.edu.eg/english/">http://www.fayoum.edu.eg/english/</a>

Address: Faiyum, 35111, Fayoum, Egypt

[ 09/09/2015 - 20/04/2020 ]

## **Pre-Master Studies in construction management**

**Fayoum University** <a href="http://www.fayoum.edu.eg/english/">http://www.fayoum.edu.eg/english/</a>

**City:** Fayoum **Country:** Egypt

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Arabic

Other language(s):

### **English**

LISTENING B2 READING C1 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2** 

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

#### **DIGITAL SKILLS**

### **Ms Office and Outlook**

Microsoft Office | Microsoft Word | Outlook | Microsoft Excel

### **BIM and CAD Technology**

Drawing software: AutoCAD, REVIT | Revit Integration With Navisworks | Autodesk BIM360 Document Management

### **Planning and Simulation**

Primavera (Basics) | SYNCHRO 4D

#### Social Media

LinkedIn | Zoom | Twitter

## COMMUNICATION AND INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

### Confidence

**Dedicaton** 

**Accountability** 

**Analyticality**